Matheus Torquato

Computer Engineer, MSc.

Contact

Summary

Swansea, Wales United Kingdom

Matheusft@gmail.com

Expertise

Artificial Intelligence,
Machine Learning,
Data Science, Data
Mining, Embedded
Computing, Digital
Systems,
Reconfigurable
Computing and
Human-Computer
Interaction.

Skills

Python, MATLAB,
TensorFlow, Scikit
Learn, Pandas,
NumPy, SciPy, Version
control systems,
Translating complex
scientific concepts to
non-experts,
Proactivity,
Organisation,
Communication,
Responsibility and
Discipline

Certification

Huawei Certified ICT Associate – Artificial Intelligence

Languages

English Portuguese

BEng and MSc in Computer Engineering. Three years of experience in applying Machine Learning to manufacturing processes. Expertise in scientific and applied research in the topics of Artificial Intelligence, Data Science, Embedded Computing, Digital Systems and Human-Computer Interaction. Well-developed skills employing scientific methods through experimental design, exploratory data analysis and hypothesis testing. Enthusiastic about utilising novel analytical approaches to address real-world challenges and improve commercial outcomes with data. Looking to learn on a daily basis, knowledge is never too much.

Experience

2018-Now **ASTUTE 2020**

Project Assistant (Machine Learning) - June to Now

• Leading the development of projects involving machine learning, data science, computer vision and optimisation.

- Designing regression, classification and predictive models for different processes in the Welsh manufacturing sector.
- Delivering actionable insights from industrial datasets focusing on supporting managerial informed decisions.

2015-2015 Tata Steel

Port Talbot, Wales, UK

Swansea, Wales, UK

Process Control Engineering Trainee - September to October

- Developed a mobile app (VB programming language) for logging field measurements, previously performed manually.
- Collaborated in the selection of power metering devices for updating the company's high voltage substation network.

2014-2014 **Petrobras**

Natal, RN, Brazil

Natal, RN, Brazil

Engineering Intern - March to May

 Assisted in the final stage of a Programmable Logic Controller ladder code development.

2014–2014 National Institute for Space Research (INPE)

Engineering Intern - January to March

 Coded a frequency-based signal detecting software (MATLAB) used by low altitude satellites.

Education

2016-2017	Masters in Computer Engineering Final Mark: 10/10 Included A Period in The SMART Lab (Ottawa, Canada) As A Visiting Researcher.
2014-2015	Undergraduate in Computer Science Swansea University - Swansea, Wales Final Mark: 7.1/10 Scholarship Awarded from The Science Without Borders Programme
2013–2015	Undergraduate in Computer Engineering UFRN - Brazil Final Mark: 9.6/10 Result Among the Top 0.16% Highest in The History of This Undergraduate Course.

Additional Activities

2021	Data Study Group Predictive maintenance of robo	Alan Turing Institute otic machining tools.
2020	Project Development Modelling ML	Github
2020	Online Course Quantitative Finance & Algorith	Udemy nmic Trading in Python
2019	Online Course Python for Financial Analysis a	und Algorithmic Trading
2018	Online Course Introduction to User Experienc	University of Michigan - edX
2015	Volunteer Researcher Future Interaction Technology Lab - Swansea University Volunteer Researcher in the field of Human-Computer Interaction.	
2014	Research Project Machine Le Embedded Applications Using	arning and Intelligent Instrumentation Laboratory - UFRN Microcontrollers and FPGA.
2013	Research Project Using Computational Tools in V	Computer Engineering Department - UFRN Wind Turbine Study.

Publications

2021	Journal Paper Evaluating the burden of COVID-19 on hospital modelling-based analysis of 14.8 million individu	
2019	Journal Paper Circui High-Performance Parallel Implementation of Go	its, Systems, and Signal Processing enetic Algorithm on FPGA.
2019	Journal Paper Parallel Implementation of Reinforcement Learni FPGA.	IEEE Accessing Q-Learning Technique for
2019	Journal Paper Deep Neural Network Hardware Implementation Autoencoder.	n Based on Stacked Sparse
2016	Journal Paper - (Honorable Mention) Emergeables: Deformable Displays for Continuaction.	CHI 2016 nous Eyes-Free Mobile Inter-